Finding Aid for Stanley B. Goldberg papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Stanley B. Goldberg Papers, 1981-1993
Goldberg, Stanley B.
0.5 linear feet (in 2 boxes)
2013098 Aa 2
Papers of Stanley B. Goldberg, president of the Wayne County, Mich., chapter of Mothers Against Drunk Driving. Collection includes correspondence, newspaper clippings, and videotapes.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Stanley B. Goldberg (Donor No. 10960 ) in July 2013.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Stanley B. Goldberg, ACSW became President of the Wayne County, Mich. chapter of Mothers Against Drunk Driving (M.A.D.D.) in 1989. His twin brother, Dr. Robert B. Goldberg, was fatally injured by a drunk driver in 1980, at the age of 32. Robert's death led to Goldberg's active involvement with M.A.D.D. Goldberg became the Wayne County M.A.D.D. chapter Treasurer in 1984, Vice-President in 1988, and the chapter's President in 1989. He also served as advisor for Students Against Driving Drunk (S.A.D.D.) chapter of Stevenson High School in Livonia, Mich.
Collection includes 2 volumes and 7 VHS videotapes. Volume 1, the larger of two volumes, includes Goldberg's correspondence dated between 1981 and 1990, a collection of clippings from Michigan newspapers related to drunk driving, victims and families of drunk drivers, legal cases against drunk drivers, M.A.D.D. ads, etc.; programs and announcements of M.A.D.D. support groups meetings, public workshops, vigils, and other activities; also M.A.D.D. bumper stickers and a few photographs. Correspondence includes exchanges between Goldberg and Michigan's elected politicians and officers of M.A.D.D. chapters, among other correspondents. Volume 2 contains material related to the annual Wayne and Oakland Counties LifeRide project. The project was designed to provide free rides to overindulged motorists on New Year's Eve. This material includes 1989-1991 publicity articles, M.A.D.D correspondence to taxi companies, taxi roster, and worksheet form. Also, photographs from the 1993 LifeRide event. Video recordings dated between 1984 and 1993 of M.A.D.D. events and meetings, and Goldberg's TV interviews aired on local channels 50, 56, 62, including an interview with Phil Donahue.
Subjects:
Goldberg, Stanley B.; Drunk driving--Michigan.; Mothers Against Drunk Driving (Organization). Wayne County Chapter (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Clippings files.; Floats (vehicles); Interviews.; Parades.; Photographs.; Videorecordings.
- Stanley B. Goldberg papers
  - Volume 1, 1981-1991 (Box 1)
  - Volume 2: Project LifeRide, 1989-1991 and 1993 (Box 1)
  - Videotapes (Box 2)
    - M.A.D.D. state conference, October 10-13, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Project LifeRide, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Project LifeRide TV interview, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Project LifeRide, 1991 (Box 2)
    - M.A.D.D. float, Holiday Parade, Livonia, Mich., November 1992 (Box 2)
    - M.A.D.D. Quilt Memorial video, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Stanley Goldberg interviews, including Phil Donahue (Box 2)
      (videotape is undated)